<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[My Stuff!!]]></title>
  <link href="http://gauthamns.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gauthamns.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-30T20:44:48+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://gauthamns.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Gautham]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google ditching Android? What a joke!!]]></title>
    <link href="http://gauthamns.github.io/blog/2013/07/30/google-ditching-android-what-a-joke/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-30T19:51:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gauthamns.github.io/blog/2013/07/30/google-ditching-android-what-a-joke</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>AppleInsider wrote a lengthy article stating Google is ditching Android!! It&rsquo;s a classic example of coming to a conclusion first and then looking for evidence. The article here: <a href="http://appleinsider.com/articles/13/07/29/google-appears-ready-to-ditch-android-over-its-intellectual-property-issues">http://appleinsider.com/articles/13/07/29/google-appears-ready-to-ditch-android-over-its-intellectual-property-issues</a> . Last article I&rsquo;ve read in AppleInsider!!</p>

<p>Why? Because Android is not making money. Why? Intellectual issues. Why? Samsung&rsquo;s dominance. Why? Decelerated progress?. Why? Chromecast not named Androidcast!! Hahaha!!</p>

<p>Android not making money? Seriously? That is why Microsoft spending billions popularizing Windows phone, firefox coming up with firefox os, Canonical, Ubuntu for phones. Android will make tons of money. From Motorola&rsquo;s hardware division, from Google services like email, app engine, from search etc etc. Do you think other divisions of Microsoft like Microsoft office would have been as popular as they have been if it were a standalone product?</p>

<p>Intellectual issues? Microsoft had to pay so much in legal fines, so much bad press, bad blood I would say. Did they give up on Windows? Given that that was their main product but Android is not so for Google. But Android will be central to Google&rsquo;s bigger aspirations. to become more than just a search engine.</p>

<p>Samsung&rsquo;s dominance? That is a cause for concern. Google should do something about it. But abondoning because of it? I believe with Google need not worry about Samsung&rsquo;s dominance. Samsung&rsquo;s software is just pathetic. Touchwiz is such a mess (not about extra features, mind you). They can never become a software company in the near future. And with Google play services, Google has made it extremely difficult to fork Android and be successful.</p>

<p>Decelerated progress? Seriously? Let&rsquo;s take a look at what&rsquo;s new in the last year in Android. New location services, Game center for Android, design standardization, exciting hardware at affordable cost (Nexus 4), and finally Android 4.3. Google is now adding many of the features through Google play services instead through Android versions. Advantages: No need to wait for the new Android version to make it to the phone, make it harder to fork Android(for Google!!)</p>

<p>Chromecast? Hahaha.. Chrome head. Business decisions. I&rsquo;m not commenting on that. Nor am I going to read too much into it.</p>

<p>Chrome head now leading Android? Sundar Pichai is credited with resounding success of Chrome browser. Google will be hoping he takes Android to new heights. Not so that he will kill the popular OS and try and make Chrome OS popular.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ActionBarCompat with NavigationDrawer]]></title>
    <link href="http://gauthamns.github.io/blog/2013/07/30/actionbarcompat-with-navigationdrawer/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-30T17:15:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gauthamns.github.io/blog/2013/07/30/actionbarcompat-with-navigationdrawer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>ActionBarSherlock was one of the most popular libraries for Android which emulated the ActionBar functionalities for lower versions of Android. Now with Google releasing Compatibility library, we can use ActionBarActivity to have actionbar in our app instead of using ActionBarSherlock.</p>

<p>I believe every app (majority of the cases) will have ActionBarCompat and NavigationDrawer. If the app is simple enough, there is no need for a NavigationDrawer. So how well do they both play with each other? Pretty well actually. I did not have any problems integrating both even though the Navigation Drawer example given by Google uses native ActionBar and for API levels higher than 14.</p>

<p>Github repo: <a href="https://github.com/gauthamns/blog-actionbarcompat.git">https://github.com/gauthamns/blog-actionbarcompat.git</a></p>

<p>The way Navigation Drawer is designed, I believe a better way to design the apps is by having a Single Activity for the whole app and changing the Fragments. (Single Activity does not mean it is only opened once, but might be opened many times with different intents. Intents are consumed by FragmentFactory class which will spit out the required Fragment for the current page.) Will write a new blog post on this.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I should Blog daily!!]]></title>
    <link href="http://gauthamns.github.io/blog/2013/07/29/first-post/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-29T23:52:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://gauthamns.github.io/blog/2013/07/29/first-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is my blog. I plan to spend some time to blog everyday. Trying out Octopress since it seems to be very simple and built for hackers!!</p>

<p>So here is what I would like to do: Every blog post will be accompanied by a Github project. Every post will have a common theme. A question. And an answer to it.</p>

<p>All posts are divided into 3 catagories: beginner, intermediate &amp; advanced.</p>

<p>Test embeding code</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="n">rake</span> <span class="n">deploy</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">fansy_super</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">is_true</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">is_true</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">end</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>




<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/996818.js'></script>
<noscript><pre><code></code></pre></noscript></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
